Guide to the Wesley C. Salmon Papers, 1950-2003 ASP.2003.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Wesley C. Salmon Papers
1950-2003
1963-2001
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Salmon, Wesley C.
ASP.2003.01
43 Linear Feet (71 document cases)
Wesley C. Salmon was an historian and philosopher of science who made major contributions to current ideas of scientific explanation, causation, and the nature of induction and probability among other areas of philosophy of science. Salmon was a professor at several major institutions including Indiana University, the University of Arizona and the University of Pittsburgh. The materials in his collection include personal and professional correspondence, manuscripts, working papers, lecture notes and their ancillary materials, versions of professional talks, and documentation from his work in professional organizations. There are also documents relating to his role in academic administration. Further, there are teaching materials and memorabilia. Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Biography
Wesley Charles Salmon was an American philosopher of science who made major contributions in many areas of the discipline. He was born in 1925 and died in 2001. His principal areas of inquiry and research included the concepts of scientific explanation, causality, and the logic of induction. Salmon was widely regarded as one of the most distinguished and productive philosophers of science of the twentieth century. He was educated at Wayne University and the University of Chicago, where he took an M.A. in 1947, and at the University of California at Los Angeles where he received a Ph.D. in philosophy in 1950. He studied under the supervision of Hans Reichenbach.
After taking his Ph.D., Salmon had a long and productive career within academia, holding positions at several major academic institutions. These include the Department of History and Philosophy of Science at Indiana University, Bloomington, where he was the Norwood Russell Hanson professor (1963-1973); the University of Arizona at Tucson (1973-1981); and the University of Pittsburgh from 1981 to 2001. At the University of Pittsburgh he was Professor and Chair of the Department of Philosophy from 1981 to 1983 and was University Professor from 1983 until he retired in 1999.
Salmon was the author of more than 100 professional articles. His introductory textbook Logic was a widely used standard for many decades. It went through many editions and was translated into several languages, including Chinese, French, German,Italian, Japanese and Spanish. He authored several works that stand as prominent landmarks of twentieth century philosophy of science. Among these are The Foundations of Scientific Inference (1967), and Statistical Explanation and the Causal Structure of the World (1984); equally significant are Four Decades of Scientific Explanation (1990) and Causality and Explanation (1998). He was a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. He served as president of the Philosophy of Science Association (1971-1972) and of the Pacific Division of the American Philosophical Association (1977 - 1978). He was also president of the UNESCO-sponsored International Union of History and Philosophy of Science (1998-1999).
Scope and Content Notes
The collection reflects the activities of a productive academic in the twentieth century. Accordingly the papers document Salmon's research, creative work, professional lectures, teaching, and professional society contributions. The collection has material from the 1930s such as volumes of Erkenntnis, some materials from the 1950s, such as a copy of Salmon's Ph.D. thesis, and some material from his first academic posts. However, the bulk of the material dates from his appointment as a professor at Indiana University in 1963 through his untimely death in 2001. The collection is organized into seven series.
The archival material includes correspondence, which is almost exclusively professional in nature. Letters and e-mails were exchanged not only with fellow philosophers of science, but also with specialists in other disciplines such as statisticians, physicists and mathematicians.
The manuscripts and working papers constitute texts that reflect Salmon's early versions of later published manuscripts, personal copies of published manuscripts, sheets on which he worked out various logical or statistical problems, and similar material. In a few cases, there are corresponding materials for certain other philosophers who sent manuscripts to him for comment.
The professional talks include overheads, annotated outlines and notes while the teaching material relates to his teaching of classes at the university level. Again there are notes, outlines of lectures, annotations, and accompanying materials. Other material in the collection document Salmon's activities in professional organizations.
The collection also contains photographs of Salmon and his associates as well as some annotated books and pre-prints reflecting Salmon's commentary on the contents of these printed materials.
Previous Citation
Wesley C. Salmon Papers, 1950-2003, ASP.2003.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh
Custodial History
All materials were owned by Wesley C. Salmon and in his possession until his death in 2001. Following his death, they were owned by and in the possession of his widow, Merrilee Salmon, who donated them to the Archives of Scientific Philosophy in 2002 and 2004.
Acquisition Information
The material in this archive was donated to the University of Pittsburgh's Archives of Scientific Philosophy by Merrilee Salmon, the widow of Wesley C. Salmon. The material was transferred in several donations between 2002 and 2004.
Access Restrictions
There are some restrictions on the access to the material in this archive: letters of recommendation written for living persons are sequestered as are Salmon's evaluations of research proposals written by living persons.
Arrangement
The archival materials are ordered into seven series, some of which are further divided into subseries.
Series I. Correspondence, 1960-2010
Series II. Manuscripts, 1957-2001
Series III. Professional Talks, 1970-2001
Series IV. Teaching Materials, 1951-2001
Series V. Professional Organizations, 1960-2000
Series VI. Photos of Salmon and Colleagues, 1951-2001
Series VII. Library Materials, 1970-2001
Science -- Philosophy -- History -- Sources; Explanation; Photographs; Lectures; Lecture notes; Correspondence; Manuscripts (Document genre); Inference; Logic; Philosophy; Science -- Philosophy; Grünbaum, Adolf; Salmon, Wesley C.
- Correspondence, 1960-2010; 1963-2001; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains all of Salmon's correspondence. The great bulk of the correspondence is professional in nature and discusses concerns Salmon had in his academic life. Salmon's interests ranged widely across philosophy of science and included logic, philosophy of mind, explanation, and other topics. Hence there are lettters to psychologists, mathematicians, physicists, and linguists as well as to and from other philosophers among the correspondence. The letters take up topics central to Salmon's philosophical concerns such as causality, logic, or scientific explanation. Salmon frequently saved copies of the letters that he sent to other people so both sides of the correspondence may be represented in the holdings. The materials are organized alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent, and within that division, chronologically.
  - Correspondents - A, 1.
    - Aberdeen University Press, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abian, Alexander, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Achinstein, Peter, 1964-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ackerman, John, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Acock, Malcolm, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Adams, E.M., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Adams, Ernest, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Adam, Marilyn, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Adams, Mary, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Adams, Robert, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Aidun, Debra, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Alan, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Alex, 1964-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Aliabadi, Y.S., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Aliseda, Atocha, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Allen, Sydney, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Allentuck, Marcia, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Alpert, Daniel, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alston, William, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Altham, J.E.J., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Alred, Kyrin, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - American Institue of Physics, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Anagnostopulous, Georgios, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Anderson, Alan, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Anderson, Myron, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Anderson, Ronald, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Angell, Richard, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Ankenbrandt, Charles, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Anne, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Antonelli, Aldo, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Armendariz, A.A., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Armstrong, David, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Areson, Richard, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Aronson, Michael, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Asquith, Peter, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Atiya, Ramez, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Audi, Robert, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Aune, Bruce, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Averill, Edward, 1969-1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Awodey, Steve, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Axinn, Sidney, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondents - B, 2.
    - Badash, Larry, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Bagne, Curtis, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Baie, A.C., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Baier, Annette, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Baier, Kurt, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Baierlein, Ralph, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Baillie, Patricia, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Baird, Davis, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Baker, Lynne, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Bakhurst, David, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Baltas, Aristides, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Baltzer, J.C., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Bandyopadhyay, Prasanta, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Banks. Ellison, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Baraff, Gary, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Bar-Hillel, Maya, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Bar-Hillel, Y, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Barbara, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Barcomb, Wayne, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Bardis, Jim, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Barfield, Esther, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Barnes, Eric, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Bartha, Paul, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Bartley, W.W., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Bartok, Philip, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Basil Blackwell Ltd., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Batens, Diderik, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Baum, Robert, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Baumer, William, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Baumrin, Bernard, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Beakley, Brian, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Bealer, George, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Beardsley, Monroe, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Beauchamp, Tom, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Beauregard, Laurent, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 76-77)
    - Beck, Lewis, 1964-1991 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Beckett, William, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Beiseckor, Dave, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Bell, Nora, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Belnap, Nuel, 1966-1987 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Ben, 1967-1989 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Benacerraf, Paul, 1964-1994 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Benditt, Theodore, 1969-1997 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Benenson, F.C., 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Benjamin, Roger, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Bennet, J., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Benloff, Paul, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Beranek, Leo, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Berge, William, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bergmann, Frithjof, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bergoffen, Debra, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Berkson, Joseph, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bernardo, Aldo, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bernardo, Giuliano di, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Berndtson, Arthur, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bernie, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Berry, Donald, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bertelsmann Distribution, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Berthold, Fred, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bevilacqua, Fabio, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Bhargavi, V., 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Biller, Alan, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Binzel, Richard, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Black, Max, 1958-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Blackwell, Kenneth, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Blair, Anthony, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Blair, David, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Blanche, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Blitzer, Leon, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Blum, Carol, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Bob, 1965-1998 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bogdan, Radu, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Boland, L., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Bolen, Ted, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bonetti, N., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Boley, Forrest, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Borchert, Donald, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Borklund, Elmer, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Borzi, Domenica, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Bostain, Mary, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bouveresse, Renee, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Bowie, Norman, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Bowles, George, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Bowman, Peter, 1964-1971 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Boyer, David, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Boyle, Matt, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Bracken, Harry, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Bradie, Michael, 1976-1992 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Bradley, Michael, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Bradnan, Andrew, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Brand, Myles, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Brandon, Robert, 1980-1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Brandt, Richard, 1966-1977 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Braun, David, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Brennen, Michael, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Brett, Peter, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Brian, 1964-1988 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Brichetto, Tony, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Brittan, Gordon, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Broackes, Justin, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Brodbeck, May, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Brody, Baruch, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Bromberger, Sylvain, 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Brower, Bruce, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Brown, Bryson, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Brubaker, Kent, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Brudny, M.I., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Brush, Stephen, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Bryan, Mary Lind, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Bub, Jeffry, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Buchanan, Harvey, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Buchdahl, Gerd, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Buck, Roger, 1966-1987 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Bugbee, Henry, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Burch, Robert, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Burge, Tyler, 1985-1992 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Burkholder, Leslie, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Burks, Arthur, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Burnette, Denise, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Burnor, Richard, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Butts, Robert, 1988-1996 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Butweir, Ms., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Corrrespondents - C, 3.
    - C, Bill, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cadwallader, Eva, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Caito, Salvatore, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cal-Tech Bookstore, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Caldwell, Robert, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Calhoun, Laurie, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Campaner, Raffaelle, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Campbell, Keith, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Canfield, John, 1965-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Carnap, Rudolf, 1959-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Carrier, Martin, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Carter, Byrum, 1966-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Carter, Lee, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Cartwright, Nancy, 1970-1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Cartwight, Richard, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Carvalho, Manoel, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Casari, Ettore, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Castaneda, Hector-Neri, 1967-1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Canton, C.E., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Catton, Philip, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Cauman, Leigh, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Cavin, Robert, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Caws, Peter, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Celli, Franca, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Chalmers, A.F., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Chaney, Newcomb, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Changizi, Mark, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Chappell, John, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Chatalian, George, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Chi, Richard, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Chiappin, Jose, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Chiara, Marisa, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Child, James, 1966-1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Chontos, Stephen, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Christensen, Ferrel, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Christensen, Ronald, 1965-1983 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Church, Alonzo, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Churchland, Paul, 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Clark, Peter, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Clark, Romane, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Clatterbaugh, Kenneth, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Clifton, Rob, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Clitheroe, Eric, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Clendinnen, John, 1965-1980 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Coburn, Robert, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Cocchiarella, Nino, 1975-1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Coffa, Jose Alberto and Linda, 1969-1985 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Coffey, J.I., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 50, Unknown item 50)
    - Cogan, Robert, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 51, Unknown item 51)
    - Conen, Alvin, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Cohen, Gordon, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Cohen, Jonathan, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Cohen. Laurence, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Cohen, Marc, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Cohen, Mendel, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Cohen, Paul, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Cohen, Robert, 1977-1985 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Cohen, Stewart, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 60, Unknown item 60)
    - Coil, Alison, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Collier, John, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Colodny, Robert, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Community of Science, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Coniglione, Francesco, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Copi, Irving, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Coppin, Jean, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Copyright Clearance Center, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Corcoran, John, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Cordero, Alberto, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Cornman, James, 1964-1976 (Box 3, Folder 71, Unknown item 71)
    - Corson, David, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Cortes, Alberto, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Costa de Beauregard, O., 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Cormack, Robert, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Costantini, Domenico, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Coulehan, Jack, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Coveney, Peter, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cowan, Ruth, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Cox, Gary, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Coyne, William, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Craig, William, 1966-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Crane, Daniel Kadane, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Cranor, Carl, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Craver, Carl, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Creary, Lewis, 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Creath, Rick, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Creel, Richard, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Cribbes, Valerie, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Crossley, John Newsome, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Crowe, Devon, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Culbertson, James, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Culler, John, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Cumming, R.A., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Cummins, Terrill, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Curd, Martin, 1979-1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Curtis, Gerald "Jerry", 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondents - D, 4.
    - D. Reidel Publishing Co., 1975-1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Dahl, Norman, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Dahlberg, James, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - D'Amato, Anthony, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - D'Amico, Robert, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Dan, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Dannreuther, Kathleen, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Danto, Arthur, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Darden, Lindley, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Darosky, Renee, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Dauer, Francis, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - David, 1978-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Davies, Michael, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Davis, E.H., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Davis, Elton "Ray", 1966-1975 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Davis, John, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Davis, J.W., 1967-1982 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Davis, Marcia, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Davis, Steven, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Day, Robert, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - De Finetti, Bruno, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - De Fuentes, Montserrat (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - De Jesus, Alirio, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Deakin, Natasha, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Deeming, William, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Delany, C.F., 1983 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Dell Publishing Co., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Dennett, Daniel, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Department of Statistics, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Dearly, Paul, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Derge, David, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Desbaugh, L.O., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Desmontes, Jacques, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Despat, Bernard, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Deutsch, Daniel, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Dever, William, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Dick, 1964-1975 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Dickason, Elly, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Dickenson Publishing Co., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Dicker, G.E., 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Dickie, George, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Dietrich, Eric, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Diggs, B.J., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Dilley, Frank, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Dilworth, Craig, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Di Prete, John, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Dolan, John, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Donagan, Alan, 1964-1982 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Dorling, John, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Doubleday and Co., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Dougherty, Jude, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Douglas, Richard, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Dover Publications, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Dowe, Jo, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Dowe, Phil, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Dray, W.H., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Dreger, Alice, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Dreher, John, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Dretske, Fred, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Driscoll, Adrian, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Drouet, P., 1991 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Drumm, Robert, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Dublin, Henry, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Ducasse, C.J., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Duchene, Josianne, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Dudkin, Vitaley, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Dudley, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Dudley, Underwood, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Duey, Laura, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Duff, Patricia, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Dufur, Theodore, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Duggan, Timothy, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Dumas, Lawrence, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Dunn, Michael, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Dunn, Thomas, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Dushkin, David, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Correspondents - E, 5.